// Quiz questions and answers:
const data = [
  {
    id: "Question 1",
    question: "Who was the 2021 world champion?",
    a: "Charles Leclerc",
    b: "Lewis Hamilton",
    c: "Sebastian Vettel",
    d: "Fernando Alonso",
    e: "Max Verstappen",
    correct: "e",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 2",
    question: "Who won the race of 2020 Sakhir?",
    a: "George Russell",
    b: "Max Verstappen",
    c: "Sergio Perez",
    d: "Valtteri Bottas",
    e: "Lando Norris",
    correct: "c",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 3",
    question: "When was Formula 1 founded?",
    a: "1980",
    b: "1943",
    c: "1960",
    d: "1930",
    e: "1950",
    correct: "e",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 4",
    question: "Who is the team principal of Mercedes-AMG F1?",
    a: "Toto Wolff",
    b: "Claire Williams",
    c: "Rob Denis",
    d: "Zak Brown",
    e: "Christian Horner",
    correct: "a",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 5",
    question: "Who will replace Sebastian Vettel in 2021?",
    a: "Sergio Perez",
    b: "Lando Norris",
    c: "Lance Stroll",
    d: "Carlos Sainz",
    e: "Alex Albon",
    correct: "d",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 6",
    question:
      "In 2013, with which car Sebastian Vettel became Formula 1 champion?",
    a: "RB6",
    b: "RB12",
    c: "RB8",
    d: "RB9",
    e: "RB7",
    correct: "d",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 7",
    question: "What will the Racing Point team called in 2021?",
    a: "McLaren",
    b: "Aston Martin",
    c: "Mercedes-AMG",
    d: "Alpine",
    e: "Williams",
    correct: "b",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 8",
    question: "How many championships does Michael Schumacher?",
    a: "7",
    b: "6",
    c: "8",
    d: "4",
    e: "5",
    correct: "a",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 9",
    question: "Who has the most wins ever?",
    a: "Michael Schumacher",
    b: "Alain Prost",
    c: "Lewis Hamilton",
    d: "Mika Hakkinen",
    e: "Ayrton Senna",
    correct: "c",
  },
  {
    id: "Question 10",
    question: "Which one of these teams arenâ€™t in F1?",
    a: "Ferrari",
    b: "Porsche",
    c: "Alpine",
    d: "Alfa Romeo",
    e: "Haas",
    correct: "b",
  },
];

// Elements:
const clickBtn = document.getElementById("click");
const main = document.querySelector("main");
const container = document.getElementById("container");
const header = document.querySelector(".header");
const idEl = document.getElementById("question_id");
const questionEl = document.getElementById("question");
const answerEls = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");
const ans_a = document.getElementById("answer_a");
const ans_b = document.getElementById("answer_b");
const ans_c = document.getElementById("answer_c");
const ans_d = document.getElementById("answer_d");
const ans_e = document.getElementById("answer_e");
const backBtn = document.getElementById("back");
const nextBtn = document.getElementById("next");

// To hide the "main" and make the container visible:
clickBtn.addEventListener("click", () => {
  main.classList.toggle("hidden");
  container.classList.add("block");
});

// Quiz questions and score:
let currentQuestion = 0;
let score = 0;

// Functions:
loadQuiz();
function loadQuiz() {
  deSelectAnswers();

  const currentQuestionData = data[currentQuestion];
  idEl.innerText = currentQuestionData.id;
  questionEl.innerText = currentQuestionData.question;
  ans_a.innerText = currentQuestionData.a;
  ans_b.innerText = currentQuestionData.b;
  ans_c.innerText = currentQuestionData.c;
  ans_d.innerText = currentQuestionData.d;
  ans_e.innerText = currentQuestionData.e;
}

function deSelectAnswers() {
  answerEls.forEach((answerEl) => (answerEl.checked = false));
}

function getValue() {
  let answer;

  answerEls.forEach((answerEl) => {
    if (answerEl.checked) {
      answer = answerEl.id;
    }
  });
  return answer;
}

// Previous Question:
backBtn.addEventListener("click", () => {
    if (currentQuestion.valueOf() === 0) {
        alert("You can't go back more!");
    } else {
    currentQuestion--;
    loadQuiz();
    }
});

// Next Question:

nextBtn.addEventListener("click", () => {
  const answer = getValue();

  if (answer) {
    if (answer === data[currentQuestion].correct) {
      score++;
    }
    currentQuestion++;

    const result = `<h2 class="js_h2 mb-2 text-3xl text-center">You answered ${score}/${data.length} questions correctly!</h2>
    <button class="js_btn bg-red-700 w-36 p-2 ml-48 rounded-md text-lg text-white text-center tracking-widest" onclick="location.reload()">Try again</button>
    `;

    if (currentQuestion < data.length) {
      loadQuiz();
    } else if (score > 7) {
      header.innerHTML = `
                <h1 class="js_h1 mb-2 text-4xl text-center">Very Good!</h1> 
                ${result}
                `;
    } else if (score > 3 && score <= 7) {
      header.innerHTML = `
                <h1 class="js_h1 mb-2 text-4xl text-center">Not Bad!</h1>
                ${result}
                `;
    } else if (score <= 3) {
      header.innerHTML = `
                <h1 class="js_h1 mb-2 text-4xl text-center">Go watch Cars 3, not F1!</h1>
                ${result}
            `;
    }
  }
});
